# NICHOLAS SEIDL

# Machine Learning Engineer

I have experience working on various **machine learning** projects, particularly focused on **computer vision** and data. I'm currently working at Apple doing data science on CV and NLP datasets, as well as data pipelining. I built a live object detector (YOLO) for Wayfair in Summer 2019. In Spring 2019, I worked on robustness analysis of Apple's Neural Face Detector. In Spring + Summer 2018, I built two web services at Apple: one for content analysis and retrieval and one for hosted image comparisons and history.

## Contact

nicholasseidl@gmail.com (650)-739-6674



nseidl.io



/in/nicholaskseidl



github.com/nseidl

# Languages

Python, Java, Javascript

# **Software**

Airflow, Kubernetes, Tensorflow, TensorRT, Keras, TFLite, CoreML, Tornado, Flask, React, Typescript, S3, EC2, Postgres, REST, Elasticsearch, Docker, nltk, pandas, numpy

### Courses

Algorithms and Data Structures Artificial Intelligence Linear Algebra Distributed Systems ML and Data Mining Object Oriented Design Computer Systems Programming Languages Probability and Statistics

#### Interests

Formula 1, Chess, Pool, Photography, Basketball, Hiking

# **Experience**

#### Apple Inc.

ISE SIML - Machine Learning Engineer

February 2020 - Present

- Computer Vision
- Natural Language Processing
- Data Science
- Cloud Compute
- Active Learning and Selection
- Robustness Analysis
- Annotation Aggregation
- Data quality and pipelining
- Email me for most up-to-date resume

## Wayfair LLC

Data Science - Computer Vision Engineer

Boston, MA June 2019 - Aug. 2019

Cupertino, CA

- Implemented YOLO(v3) neural network for <u>live on-device object detection</u>
- Optimized with quantization, CUDA, cuDNN, TensorRT, and Tensor Cores
- Achieved 80x speedup in inference time and up to 4x smaller model sizes

#### Apple Inc.

C&P CVML - Machine Learning Engineer

Cupertino, CA Jan. 2019 - June 2019

- Analyzed failures of face detector to target aggressors and guide development
- Designed and automated robustness analysis pipeline: inference → detection evaluation → robustness analysis → visualization
- Managed data collection, selection, and annotation (guidelines, spec, and quality)

#### Apple Inc.

Cupertino, CA Jan. 2018 - Aug. 2018

IMG QE - Full Stack Software Engineer

- Content Collection: audio/image/video/stream analysis and retrieval
  - Integrated blob (Amazon S3) and metadata (Postgres) stores to serve content
  - Extracted attributes from audio, image, video, and stream content (Swift)
- Image Comparisons: image comparison web service with history
  - Rewrote backend in Flask; expanded API for frontend and hosted comparisons

### **Education**

### **Northeastern University**

Boston, MA Sep. 2015 - Dec. 2019

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science Khoury College of Computer Sciences

GPA: 3.6 / 4.0